<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSMCBBOY</title>
    <description>Hi, my name is Niels Bantilan. I like to be creative with code.
</description>
    <link>http://cosmicbboy.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cosmicbboy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 17:44:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 17:44:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Origins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is true whether we’re referring to our lives, relationships, careers,
hobbies, and even this website :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this inaugural post, I’d like to tell you a little bit about the motivation
behind this blog. As a data scientist by trade I’ve started to see the world
from quite a strange perspective, and it is this mental framework that I want
to share with you through data-driven storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this framework, every phenomenon becomes a question that, &lt;strong&gt;in theory&lt;/strong&gt;,
can be answered by gathering, reshaping, and modeling data. With this kind of
“datasmithery”, we can detect patterns (or noise disguised as patterns) that
would otherwise be undetectable with human intuition alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How do &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ams.usda.gov/fooddeserts/fooddeserts.aspx&quot;&gt;food deserts&lt;/a&gt;
form in an urban context?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Can breakdancing be an effective way to teach kids about exercise?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How do non-profit humanitarian organizations share knowledge to inform their
current and future efforts?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How will labor and capital evolve with the accelerating pace of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://dupress.com/articles/intelligent-automation-a-new-era-of-innovation/&quot;&gt;intelligent automation&lt;/a&gt;?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of questions are fascinating to me, and I’ve found that framing
these questions in terms of data pipelines that can address a wide range of
hypotheses is central to my field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of telling you what that process is like, I’d like to show you instead
by sharing some stories with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-NB&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 20:30:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://cosmicbboy.github.io/blog/2015/12/04/Origins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cosmicbboy.github.io/blog/2015/12/04/Origins.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
